The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
400 years ago
All the Nascent Soul leaders of Zhao have arrived.
Greetings Envoy.
Everyone,
the country of Zhao has been stuck at rank 3 for too long.
We need a talented cultivator who can grow quickly
and reach the level of Soul Formation.
If our plan succeeds
the country of Zhao will become a rank 4 cultivation country.
Grow quickly ?
Lord Envoy, you are brillant.
This could be our chance.
Lord Envoy,
may I ask what kind of plan you have ?
We just need to gather all the Spirit Roots of Zhao
and feed this endless unused spiritual energy
to a single talented individual.
It can speed up the cultivation
so that one can reach Soul Formation.
This...
Taking the Spirit Roots of the mortals ?
Cultivators should not interfere with the lives of mortals.
I'm afraid...
The Ancestors will make the right decision.
Everything is ready, we should seize this opportunity.
I gathered you here today
to decide who that talented person will be.
Lord Envoy,
If mortals lose their Spirit Roots,
they will lose the ability to cultivate
and our sects of Zhao will not have any new disiples...
This will be the last generation of cultivators.
Envoy, please think twice about it.
Think twice ?
Lord Envoy, calm down.
It's fellow cultivators that need to think twice.
This plan
will not destroy the mortal world.
If the Country of Zhao reaches rank 4
the availability of ressources will increase.
The spiritual energy from the Spirit Roots will be returned to the mortals.
There is no need to worry about the next generation.
Lord Envoy,
my Teng Family is the top cultivation family in Zhao.
We have many talented individuals.
The Teng Family
has already formed cultivation pairs with geniuses of many sects.
We have power all over Zhao,
we can quickly set up formations in the Spirit Veins everywhere
and gather the Spirit Roots.
My Teng Family is definitely be the best choice for this plan.
Good.
I have put the Spirit Gathering Formation in this jade.
When your Teng Family is ready,
you can start extracting the Spirit Roots.
I will choose the lucky one from your Teng Family.
Thank you Lord Envoy,
the Teng Family will not disappoint you !
Piao Nanzi,
your Xuan Dao Sect
doesn't need to go to the Foreign Battelfield this time.
From now on, your Xuan Dao Sect
will provide assistance to the Teng Family.
Understood...
Lord Envoy...
Brother Piao,
if I die here
Lord Envoy will not let you live either.
If it weren't for Lord Envoy's order,
do you think I would protect your Teng Family ?
Piao Nanzi
Xuan Dao Sect Leader
Late stage Nascent Soul
Do you think you can protect him alone ?
Who are you ?
You !
Teng Huayuan !
Do you dare to fight me ?
It's you !
It turns out he grew to such a level...
Break !
Not gonna die ?
Since you're able to block this attack,
Piao Nanzi, you're indeed the top expert of Zhao.
I want to see
how long you will last.
For 400 years,
Lin Yi, the Envoy of Heaven's Tower
interfered with the development of Zhao.
To save my Xuan Dao Sect,
I had to collude with the Teng Family.
Now the country of Zhao
is in a state of chaos
and the mortal world is collapsing...
Yet I must help the wicked to destroy Zhao...
Greetings Lord Envoy.
Since you uprooted my hundred years old plan,
you deserve to die.
However,
if you hand over the Heaven Defying Bead,
I will spare your life
and let you use the Spirit Veins.
How does it sound ?
Lord Envoy !
I said that
those who help Teng Huayuan
must die !
You have good spells
but compared to me
you are insignificant.
Little brat,
you will regret this.
I have been waiting for this for a long time !
Divine Retribution ?
Take my place !
Consider it an honor.
Burning your lifespan ?
What are you doing ?!
Now that it has come to this, you want to escape ?
Do you think the mortals of Zhao will agree ?
What the hell are you talking about ?
I am the Envoy of Heaven's Tower !
I was able to hold you back enough...
I am satisfied...
I calculated everything...
But I never expected the Teng Family
could be destroyed by a small fry like you !
It's ridiculous...
Don't be so presomptuous.
Look !
You are the one who sacrified them.
Their souls are leaving their bodies
because you killed them with your own hands.
You forced me to !
Wang Lin,
I curse you
to die alone,
to have a terrible death !
Teng Huanyuan,
how did you find my hometown ?
You will never know.
Not willing to talk ?
I will.
Gao Qiming from the Piao Miao Sect
helped me find your family using his divination spells.
Gao Qiming...
I will remember this name.
You...
can go to hell.
Gao Qiming
Piao Miao Sect Leader
Late stage Nascent Soul
A memory formation ?
400 years ago,
I was asked by Teng Huayuan
to find the hometown of a Foundation Establishment cultivator.
It caused a great disaster.
But I protected the bloodline of Wang Tiantu, your family.
I believe in the heaven and earth
and in the cycle of cause and effect.
As I have forseen, I will die today.
Please don't involve the Piao Miao Sect.
Father...
Mother...
I have avenged you.
I will now embark on my own path.
Senior Situ,
the day I reach Soul Transformation
is the day you will awaken
and regain your freedom.
Dear, Tie Zhu,
let's eat.
400 years
passed in the blink of an eye.
When I was young, I wanted my parents to be respected
so I stepped in the cultivation world.
Unexpectedly, mortal and Immortal are separated.
To get my revenge,
I had to kill my way through
and force myself to get stronger.
Now that my revenge is done,
I can leave this place
to explore this vast universe
that is brimming with life.
I, Wang Lin, will never stop growing.
I will defy the heavens.
No matter how difficult the journey is,
I will forge my own path.
That's because...
if my cultivation is not high enough,
I cannot protect the people that are important to me.
My son, it doesn't matter if you are not chosen.
You can always come back,
we will always be there for you.
Tie Zhu...
you look like an Immortal now.
I have never been so proud in my life.
From now on, I will teach you cultivation.
Focus your mind on your breathing !
I want to stay in the Cloud Sky Sect.
Only here do I have the right conditions to try to refine grade 6 pills.
That way I can be useful to you in the future.
I guess it's about time to tell you that the whole subplot of the Spirit Veins is donghua original. I think it was added to dilute Wang Lin's genocide of the Teng Family. In the novel he just killed every single one of them in cold blood (except Teng Xiuxiu).
Another way they dilute Wang Lin's actions is by making Teng Huayuan use the Reverse Formation to kill his family himself to get stronger. None of that happens in the novel, just a pure massacre.
I've had my share of wounds,
now I want to fight back.
Is my destiny a wall of restrictions
that's blocking all my hopes
for life ?
My flesh and blood witnessed the past,
my adversity pushed me to brave the waves.
How do you navigate through the years passing by ?
Nirvana and rebirth are no longer
out of reach.
Immortals
are obsessed with delusions of grandeur.
Renegades
seek to crush the impermanence of the heavens.
Don't tell me that I overestimate myself
and that the path to revenge leads to hell
because I don't see the harm in that.
My new body opens its eyes
and awakens from its dream.
I have overcome many trials
to get this body back.
No matter how many endless dark nights go by,
I can still see.
By sticking to this thought, I will get it done
by my own hands.
Returning to my body opened my eyes,
I need to continue my Immortal journey.
With a flick of a finger,
only my indomitable heart remains.
Life and death trials temper me, I am not afraid of losing my soul.
Even if there are countless tribulations and hardships.
Overcome this fate, smash through the obstacles,
like the descent of a god.